# Volodymyr Kniaziev

Senior Java Developer/Team Lead

### About Me

Hi, my name's Volodymyr and I'm a senior Java developer, have 5+ years of commercial experience.

During that time I participated in different projects: fin-tech, gaming, resource managment, and e-commerce. I was involved in longterm projects which gave me strong experience in various areas of software design and development.

My primary interests are connected with Java, programming, reading professional books, discovering new technologies, and implementing it in my day-to-day work. Nevertheless I'm always open to new challenges and accept them with interest and enthusiasm.

I'm skilled in problem-solving. Besides that, I'm an open-minded and goal-oriented person and have an active teamwork attitude and quick learning ability.

# Experience

#### countries actively digitize their used car business with AUTO1 technologies and services. More than 500 microservice are running in production. Auto1

#### Senior Software Developer/ **Team Lead**

may 2021 - now

https://www.auto1-group.com

### **Responsibilities:**

Requirements analysis, Estimation, Prioritization, Design, Tasks distribution, Feature Releasing, Coordinating team activity, Server-side functionality implementation, Code reviewing, Bug fixing, Unit and Integration testing, Interviewing

It's Europe's largest wholesale platform for used cars. More than 60,000 partner dealers in over 30

### **Technologies used:**

Java, Spring Cloud, Spring Boot, Spring Data, Hibernate, Flyway, Maven, AWS, Docker, Redis, Postgres, Kibana, Grafana

# Luxoft/DXC **Technologies**

Senior Software Developer/ Team Lead

september 2019 - may 2021 https://www.luxoft.com

### It's a PAAS with customization capability for each customer's needs that's been built on microservice architecture. Customers can have different functionality for online/offline monitoring, diagnostic, and prognostic devices. All functionality was created from scratch with strong performance requirements.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Requirements analysis, Estimation, Prioritization, Tasks distribution, Coordinating team activity, Server-side functionality implementation, Bug fixing, Performance testing, Code reviewing, Unit and Integration testing, Interviewing

#### **Technologies used:**

Java, Spring Cloud, Spring Boot, Spring Data, Design, Spring Security, Hibernate, Flyway, Gradle, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, Ehcache, Multithreading, Postgres, Ignite, Cassandra, JMeter, Grafana

# Playtika

**Software Developer** 

june 2018 - september 2019 https://www.playtika.com

It's a bunch of online slot machines built on microservice architecture. Users can choose each slot machines and play, win coins or bonuses. All backend is based on Spring Cloud components, front-end is written on C# and includes Facebook and mobile clients.

## **Responsibilities:**

Requirements analysis, Server-side functionality implementation, Integration with microservices, Code reviewing, Bug fixing, Unit and Integration testing

## **Technologies used:**

Java 8, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Data, Maven, Guice, Couchbase, Kafka

## PrivatBank

**Software Developer** 

may 2017 - june 2018 https://privatbank.ua

It's the biggest Ukrainian bank with its own development team provides powerful innovative functionality in fin-tech. I have been involved in the building of different services: online purchasing of gasoline, cards design, and funds transferring between customer accounts.

## **Responsibilities:**

Requirements analysis, Server-side functionality implementation, Bug fixing, Unit testing.

## **Technologies used:**

Spring, Maven, MyBats, Redis, Postgresgl, MySgl, Tomcat, JSP

# Education

# **Ukrainian State University of** Chemical **Technology**

2017 - 2019

Master's Degree in Computer Sciences

# Dnipropetrovsk **University of Economics and** Law

2010 - 2015

Master's Degree in Finance

# Hobibes

- Motorcycling
- CrossFit
- Boxing